Guide to the William Saroyan Notebooks, 1932-1939
Department of Special Collections
- March 1939. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Small format Memorandum notebook, approx. 2.5" x 6". 23 pp. have entries. Addresses in publishing world; friends, acquaintances: Pollinger, Hairenek, Bezzerides, Hiler, Fante, John Garfield, Covarrubias, Jo Pagano, Sanora Babb.
- March 27, 1939. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Approx. 5.5" x 7". l2 pp. have entries. Train trip from Tucson to Nogales. Play & radio program imagined. Herb Caen; Notes on people, images from trip (skimpy). "The colored Porter who for 22 years tried to read a time table - never succeeded...he had heard about a man who wanted to better himself." In Guadalahara he visited (looked at) orphanage, brewery, Univ (?). red light district (?), flowering trees.
- April 1, 1939 - Beacon Writing Tablet, unruled. Three pp of Mexican notes. Nogales. Where the women were was a "miserable place". "too much trouble to get it all down. will have to remember." (Box 3, Folder 5)
- November 30, 1939 - December 2, 1939. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Blue Horse #500 Note Book. "Fall 1939 / Coming Home from N.Y. by car." 34 leaves, all loose, have skimpy pencil notes. Single line entries of titles for stories to be written; e.g. "You too Can Be A Dope"; Work to Do: "Prepare Love's Song...work on A Native American". Thanksgiving day in Odessa, Texas. Later... "Come on a my house, my louse.. I'm gonna give you candy / Armen Song." WS would write a best selling hit song with this title later.